Preliminary Guide to the Special Collections Department, Gelman Library records, 1819-2014 RG0110
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Special Collections Department, Gelman Library records
1819-2014
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
RG0110
37.5 Linear Feet
Special materials was always a part of the University's library collections; however, it was not until 1973, and the opening of the Gelman Library, that the University's special materials were housed together in proper storage and service areas. Materials in this collection include publications on the Elliott School of International Affairs, the symposium at GW on George Gamow, Baptist Church materials, bibliographies of faculty publications. and other exhibit materials including programs, postcards, labels, and videocasettes.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Acquisition information for this accession is unavailable.
Historical or Biographical Note
Special materials was always a part of the University's library collections; however, it was not until 1973, and the opening of the Gelman Library, that the University's special materials were housed together in proper storage and service areas. Before the construction of the Lisner Library in 1939, many of the collections' rare books and materials were stored in Columbian House. After the completion of Lisner, they were transferred to a large vault on the fourth floor of the new library. When the Special Collections Division was set up in the Gelman Library, many rare items, long ago packed away, were brought to light. The Special Collections Department began in 1968 as part of the Lisner Library.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include signage for exhibits and events, gifts, proposed and rejected, statistics, correspondence, theses, projects, biographical information, notes, faculty authors' information, 143 slides on the history of GW libraries, 37 slides on the history of cheerleading, 33 slides on the history of the Elliott School of International Affairs, photographs, posters, 25th anniversaries of the Gelman Library, photographs and prints used in the World War II exhibit, oral history transcripts, photocopies of books, videotapes from the April 12, 1996 Symposium at GW on George Gamow, Baptist Church materials, bibliographies of faculty publications, accession records, and other exhibit materials including programs, postcards, labels, and videocasettes. One of the exhibits was to commemorate the 35th anniversary of the March on Washington and another exhibit was titled "The President's Physician: The Life And Legacy Of Dr. Janet G. Travell." The collection covers the years 1819 to 2014.
Formerly RG 17.3.4
Collection Organization
Organized in 20 series: Proposed gifts; Statistics, correspondence, exhibit materials; Faculty Author program; Acquisitions; Exhibit files, Exhibit; Slides; Public programming; Photographs and posters; Faculty publications, Photographs, George Washington University; Transcripts, papers, correspondence; Exhibits and collections; Janet G. Travell exhibit; March on Washington exhibit, and Exhibits, Events, UA Records Management Program, and Diversity Fellowship student projects collection; Accession Records
Washington (D.C.); Color slides; Photographs; Gifts; Exhibitions; Melvin Gelman Library; Foggy Bottom (Washington, D.C.); George Washington University; George Washington University. Library; Gelman Library. Special Collections Dept.
- Proposed gifts, 1994-1995; RG0110 Series 1; 1.5 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes proposed and rejected gifts from the Special Collections department in the Gelman Library. They range in date from 1994-95.
  Formerly ACC#443
  This series has a container list in electronic form, please ask staff for assistance.
- Statistics, correspondence, exhibit materials, 1987-1990; RG0110 Series 2; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series includes statistics, correspondence, theses, projects, and exhibits materials. They range in date from 1987-90.
  Formerly ACC#444
- Faculty authors program, 1996; RG0110 Series 3; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series includes information on the faculty authors exhibit program information and a reception videotape from 1996.
  Formerly ACC#537
  - Documents and Reception Videotape, 1996; Series 3; 1.5 Linear Feet (Box 1)
  - Faculty Authors Book Signing Reception - Photographs and Negatives, 29 April 1993-October 1994; 1993; Series 3 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Faculty authors include:
    Jeffrey Anderson Michael Feldman Jonathan Fife Alf Hiltebeitel Teresa Ann Murphy Peter Rollberg Ching-Yao Shieh Christopher Stern Irene Thompson Peter Caws Rebecca Jackson C. Dianne Marin Ann Romines Stuart A. Umpleby Oscar N. Garcia Paul Malone III Gail Kern Paster Leo P. Ribaffo Lois G. Schaberer William G. Wells, Jr. Michael J. Worth Joe Jeff Goldblatt William E. Halal Rodicia Simion William G. Wells Jonathan Chaves Robert F. Dyer Ernest H. Forman J. Davidson Frame Marcel C. LaFollette Nikitas Alexandridis Yvonne Captain Irving I. Glick Jeffrey B. Harvey Claudia Tate Amitai Etzioni Jerrold M. Post Ruth Wallace Peter Brock Linda Grant DePauw Seyyed Hossin Nasr Stephen Livingston Howard Sachar Carl Steiner
  - Faculty Authors Book Signing Reception - Photographs and Negatives, 8 December 1994-2 April 1996; Series 3 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Cynthia Burack Elisabeth Fisher Ray Charles Rist Debra Sheldon Marshall W. Alcorn, Jr. Gerald W. Brock Lisa St. Clair Harvey James O. Horton Stephen Joel Trachtenberg Ali Cambel Maxine Claire Marie Malaro Carol Sigelman J. Davidson Frame Joe Jeff Goldblatt Lisa Delpy Salah S. Hassan Faye Moskowitz Kenneth Schaffner Jan-Mitchell Sherrill Hossein Askari Akos Vertes Jarol Manheim Young-Key Kim-Renawd Roland Perusse Robert Eisen Edward Berkowitz Robert Paul Churchill Charles T. Stewart, Jr. Peter Caws Tsung O. Cheng Nicholas Paley Eugene W. Kelly Stephen Eastaugh Janet Steele Susan Tolchin
  - Faculty Authors Book Signing Reception - Photographs, Negatives, and Slides, 16 May 1996-16 October 1997; Series 3 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Tom Blanton Valerie Lester Jeff Henig Henry Nau Richard Thornton Michele Zaros Michael Harmon Donald Hawkins James Oliver Horton Joseph Przytzyki Richard Schlagel Cornelius E. Therney Phyllis Langston Kim Moreland James Kaser Jorge Garcia Maria Zea David DeGrazia John Logsdon Richard Stott Carol Kochhar Lynda West Michael Alleyne Carol Thayer Cox Barry Cohen Seyyed Nasr Christopher Sten Gerald Brock Amitai Etzioni Joe Goldblatt Emmet Kennedy Henry Steiner Frederic Siegel James Willis Robb Andrew Altman Jeffrey Jerome Cohen Saundra Maley Christopher H. Sterling Jane Shore Sylvia Morotta Karen Ahlquist Susan Tolchin Francine Henderson Dan Barthel Caroline Long
  - Faculty Authors Book Signing Reception - Photographs and Negatives, 22 January 1998-16 September 1999; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Richard Thornton Elinor Solomon John Kwoka Wayne Miller Jennifer DeVere Brody Shoko Hamano Eamon Harper William Parke David Anderson Akbar Montaser Alf Hitelbeitel Barbara Miller Joel Kuipers Robert Stone Diane Bell Cynthia McClintock Nicholas Vonortas Laura Youens Roy Richard Grinker Ann Romines Susan Sell Stephen J. Trachtenberg Edward D. Berkowitz William E. Halal Kim J. Hartswick Bonnie J. Morris
  - Faculty Authors Book Signing Reception - Photographs and Negatives, 10 February 1999-5 October 2001; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Nancy Dixon Michael Marquardt Larry Yu Jeffrey R. Henig Yoon S. Park Juras T. Ryfa Marc Saperstein Christine Meloni Cynthia Leenerts George Bozzim Peter F. Klaren Aseem Prakash Roy Richard Grinker Gayle Freda Wald Eric Cline Dennis W. Johnson Bill Chambliss Judith L. Harris Ronald Spector Dalia Kaye Judith Plotz Subnasish Dasgupta Dalia Kaye Judith Plotz Sabhasish Dasgupta
  - Faculty Authors Book Signing Reception - Photographs and Negatives, 1 February 2002-2 April 2004; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Anbinder P. Chu Philip Jacks J. Przytycki Amitai Etzioni Meloni Vlach Dickson Brinkerhoff Shambaugh Cottrol Squires Turner Brock Buntman Millar Sterling
    Also includes farewell party for La Nina Clayton, Collection Development Librarian, December 2003.
  - Faculty Authors Book Signing Reception - Photographs and Negatives, undated; Series 3 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Joe Jeff Goldblatt Jane Shore
- Acquisitions, RG0110 Series 4; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 4, Box 1)
  This series includes material on acquisition negotiations.
  This series is unprocessed, please ask staff for assistance.
- Exhibits, 1935-2010; RG0110 Series 5; 8.25 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  Exhibit planning materials are arranged chronologically. The bulk of the photographs and negatives are at the end of the series and are arranged chronologically.
  Series 5 contains material accumulated throughout the preparation and execution of exhibits in Gelman Library. This material includes notes, corresondence, plans and diagrams of exhibit layouts, research material, photocopies of displayed material, photographs, negatives, captions, catalogs, programs, brochures, loan agreements, and guest books. The material dates between 1935 and 2003, with the bulk between 1973 and 2003.
  - Slides and exhibit guide to the 35th anniversary of the March on Washington, 1998; Series 5 (Box 1)
    General note
    Housed in 3-ring binder
    Formerly ACC#716
  - Exhibits - General, Undated; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1935 "Rare Books", RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1956 "Documents and Photographs From the Permanent Collection", June 15 - September 15 1956; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Frederick Kuh, Undated; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fore-Edge Book Exhibit, Undated; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1973 (November 8) "Library Science at GWU", 8 November 1973; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1974 (March 9) John Russell Mason, 9 March 1974; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1974 (September 16 - October 31) "GW Research Group", 16 September - 31 October 1974; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1975 (January 15 - February 15) "Judaica", 15 January - 15 February 1975; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1976 (February - March) "Illustrious GW Alumni", February - March 1976; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1976 (May 17 - September 30) "The Presidents: 1789 - 1974 (Crain Presidential Medals), 17 May - 30 September 1976; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1976 - October, 1980- October/November Repeat "Travels and Explorations in North America", October 1976, October-November 1980; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1976 December "Centennial Glass" loan: Diehl + Thompson, December 1976; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1976 December Illuminations (hallway), December 1976; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1976 December American Revolution Books (Student), December 1976; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1977 January - February "Inaugural Memorabilia", January - February 1977; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1977 "Rites of Spring", RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1977 September - October "Classical Education", September 1977; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1978 May repeated September 1982 "Clifford Berryman Cartoons", May 1978, September 1982; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1978 Summer "Summer in Washignton", RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1978 March - November (Main Floor) "Neighborhood Conservation", March - November 1978; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 1978 November - December "Scientific Community in Washingotn DC 1870-1900", November - December 1978; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 1979 February (Library lobby) Eistein Centenary, February 1979; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 1979 Summer "Washington DC during the Civil War", RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 1979 September - October (Loan: G.M. Barringer) "American Publishers' Decorated Cloth Bindings 1836-1933", September 1979; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 1979 February - March "McManaway Shakespeare Collection", February - March 1979; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 1979 November - 1980 February "A Collectors Choice" (Box 2, Folders 27)
  - 1980 (February - March) "George Washington Memorabilia", February - March 1980; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 1980 March - April "Hamlet From The McManaway Collection Labels", MArch - April 1980; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - 1980 (December - January 1981) "Documenting American istory Manuscripts of Presidents", December 1980 - January 1981; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 1981 May-June "Saydam Drawings to Washington Past and Present", May - June 1981; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 1981 August - September (Lobby) "Center For Washington Area Studies", August - September 1981; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - 1981 September - October "Titiam Ramsay Peale 1799 - 1885", September - October 1981; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 1981 September-October "Titian Ramsay Peale 1799-1885", September - October 1981; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Titan Ramsay Peale Early Drafts of Catalog, 1981; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 1981 (September-October) "Titian Ramsey Peale, 1799-1885", September - October 1981; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - November 1981 - January 1982 "Smith Gift Art Books", 1981 November - January 1982; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - 1982 Summer "Patterns and Pegs: 19th c. Architecture Books", Summer 1982; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - 1982 (September - October) "West African History", September - October 1982; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - 1982 (November - December) "New Resources in Art History", November - December 1982; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - 1983 January - Febrary Vladimir Nabokov "Master of Versatility", January - February 1983; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1983 March Luther Rice, March 1983; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1983 (May 24 - August 15) "Zentay Collection", May 24 - August 15 1983; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - September 1983 - January 1984 "Washington In The Age of Jackson", RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - May 12 1984 - April 25 1985 "Diamonds in the Rough", RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1984 (June 1 - August 24) "Hookers of Washignton", June 1 - August 24 1984; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - October 1984 - January 1985 "Millionth Volumes", RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1984 "Faculty Authors" Folder 1 of 4, RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1984 "Faculty Authors" Folder 2 of 4, RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1984 "Faculty Aurhtors" Folder 3 of 4, RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1984 "Faculty Authors" Folder 4 of 4, RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1985 March "Franz Bader", March 1985; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 1985 May - September "GW In The 20's", May - September 1985; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 1985 (December 6 - February 28 1986) "Diamonds in the Rough", 6 December 1985 - 28 February 1986; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1986 December "Carnegie Exhibit", December 1986; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1987 (February 5 - March 20) "Washington Artist's Books: An Overview", 5 February - 20 MArch 1987; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1987 (April 20 - May 1) "From Bones to Books - The Chinese Book Throughout History" c: Keller, 20 April - 1May 1987; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1988 "Recent Acquisitions", RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 1988 (Fall - ?) "First Fifty Years of the Columbian College.", RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 1988 (October - December) "The First 50 Years of the Columbian College", October - December 1988; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 1989-1991 "Exhibits - General", RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 1989 (January 3 - 31) "The United States Presidential Inauguration and the City of Washington" c: Gilmore, 3 - 31 January 1989; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 1989 (January 3 - 31) "The United States Presidential Inauguration and the City of Washington" c:Gilmore, 3 - 31 January 1989; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 1989 (January 3 - 31) "The United States Presidential Inauguration and the City of Washington" c:Gilmore, 3 - 31 January 1989; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 1989 (April 3 - 28) "President Stephen Joel Tachtenberg: A new Era for The George Washington University.", 3 - 28 April 1989; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - 1989 (June 5 - July 31) "Bicentennial of the French Revolution", 5 June - 31 July 1989; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 1989 (June 5 - July 31) "Bicentennial of the French Revolution", 5 June - 31 July 1989; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - 1989 (June 5 - July 31) "Bicentennial of the French Revolution", 5 June - 31 July 1989; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - 1990 (June - August) "The Limitied Editions Club" Disk, Signs, Label, June - August 1990; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1990 (June - August) "The Limitied Editions Club" Graphics, June - August 1990; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1990 (October 1 - December 14) Washington Mapping Exhibit, 1 October - 14 December 1990; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1990 (October 1 - December 14) "Washington Mapping Exhibit", 1 October - 14 December 1990; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1990 (October 1 - December 14) "Washington Mapping Exhibit", 1 October - 14 December 1990; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1991 (January 21 - March 22) "Visual Resources for Research" c: Chouiniere, 21 January - 22 March 1991; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1991 (May ?) "Many Voices on a Common Ground: The Urban Odessey of Washington D.C. Conference and Exhibition", May 1991; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1991 (May 13 - June 7) "The Abbey of St. Gaul: A Cultural Center", 13 May - 7 June 1991; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1991 (May 13 - June 7) "The Abbey of St. Gaul: A Cultural Center" c: Towers, 13 May - 7 June 1991; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1991 (August 19 - September 6) "'Artists' Books: Interaction with the Larger Culture" c: Chouiniere, 19 August - 6 September 1991; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1991 (November 4 - December 13) "Political Cartoonery in Washingtonn DC" c: Chouiniere, 4 November - 13 December 1991; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 1992 (January 6 - January 24) "A Struggle Without Hate: The Civil Rights Movement in Washignton DC" c: Henderson, 6 January - 24 January 1992; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 1992 - 1993 "Exhibits - General", RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 1992 (February 10 - February 28) "The Voteless City, Home Rule for the District of Columbia" c: Chouiniere, 10 February - 28 February 1992; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 1992 (May 4 - June 5) "1992 Alumni Reunion Weekend: A Special Exhibit", 4 May - 5 June 1992; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 1993 - 1994 "Exhibits - General", RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 1993 (June 14 - September 17) "Our Disappearing Art Heritage: Nineteenth Century English and American Book Illustrations, Designs and Bindings Fugate Exhibit" c: Henderson, 14 June - 17 September 1993; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 1993 (June 14 - September 17) "Our Disappearing Art Heritage: Nineteenth Century English and American Book Illustrations, Designs and Bindings Fugate Exhibit" c: Henderson, 14 June - 17 September 1993; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 1993 (October 4 - 29) "Gelman Library 20th Anniversary Exhibit" c: Anderson and Henderson, 4 - 29 October 1993; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 1993 (November 15 - December 31) "Charting Religious Horizons: Holy Land Maps from the Halperin Collection" c:Kaser, 15 November - 31 December 1993; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 1994 - 1995 "Exhibits General", RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - 1994 (January 19 - February 15) "Contemporary Jewelry as Personal Adornment in portugal" c: Henderson, 19 January - 15 February 1994; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - 1993 "Ilegitimmos-Joias Portuguesis Contemporaneas", RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - 1994 (January 27 - February 25) "Lost in the City: An African - American Perspective of the Nation's Capital" Colonnade Gallery c: Henderson, 27 January - 25 February 1994; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - 1994 (October 21 - October 28) "Karen Blixen/Isak Dinesen Travelling Exhibition: A Panorama of Photographs from Her Life", 21 October - 28 October 1994; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - 1994 (March 14 - April 15) "Faculty Research at GWU: Scholorship and Innovation" c: Anderson, 14 March - 15 April 1994; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - 1994 (April 20 - May 27) "Student Passions: The Fine Art of Collecting", 20 April - 27 May 1994; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - 1994 (June 13 - July 22) "Permanent Residents (Washignton Cemeteries)", 13 June - 22 July 1994; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - 1994 (August 29 - September 23) " Treasures from the Collection" c: Kaser, 29 August - 23 September 1994; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - 1994 (October 3 - October 21) "The Columbian Women of the George Washington University: A Centennial Celebration.", 3 October - 21 October 1994; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - 1994 (October 31 - November 23) "A Friend of the People: Friendship House Celebrates 90 Years of Social Progress" c: Choiniere, 31 October - 23 November 1994; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - 1994 (October 31 - November 23) "A Friend of the People: Friendship House Celebrates 90 Years of Social Progress" c: Chouiniere, RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - 1994 (December 5 - January 13, 1995) "Celebrating the Wonderful World of Charles Dickens" c: Kaser, 5 December 1994 - 13 January 1995; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - 1995 (April 17 - May 12) City Invincible: Walt Whitman's Washington, 17 April - 12 May 1995; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - 1995 (May 22 - July 28) From Plantagenet to Saxe-Coburg: Map from the Fiat Lux Library, 22 May - 28 July 1995; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - 1995 - 1996 "Exhibits Schedule", RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - 1995 (October 25) "Traveling Exhibit: Lost in the City" Photocopies, 25 October 1995; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1995 (October 25) "Traveling Exhibit: Lost int he City", 25 October 1995; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1995 (September 5 - October 20) "A CApital Commitment: The Committee of 100 on the Federal City" c: Chouiniere, 5 September - 20 October 1995; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1995 (October 30 - November 24) "Gratefully Yours: 175 Years of Library Gifts", 30 October - 24 November 1995; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 1995 (December 4 - January 26 1996) Our Other Lives: The Creators and Collectors of the Gelman Library, 4 December 1995 - 26 January 1996; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 1995 (October 25)"Traveling Exhibit: Lost in the City Exhibit Information Ect., 25 October 1995; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 1996 (February 5 - March 1) Lost in the City and African American Research Treasures, 5 February - 11 March 1996; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 1996-1997 Exhibits Schedule, RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 1996 (November 4 - February 28 1997) Inaugural Celebrations in the Nation's Capital Catalogs, 4 November 1996 - 28 February 1997; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 1996 (November 4 - February 28 1997) Inaugural Celebrations in the Nation's Capital Exhibition Cards, 4 November 1996 - 28 February 1997; RG 0110 Series 5 (Box 5, Folder 10)